Jordy Bukonda Tshibangu

Software Engineer

Details

Address

87 Park Road, Wynberg Cape Town, 7700 South Africa

Phone

0682866579

Email

jordytshibss@gmai.com

Date / Place of birth

1 August 1997 Kinshasa , Republic Democratic of Congo

Nationality

Congolese

Skills

Adaptability

• • • •

Ability to Work in a Team

 \bullet

Communication

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Good team worker

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Decision Making Skills

• • • •

Eager to learn

.

Problem Solving Skills

• • • • •

Fast Leaner

• • • •

Detail-oriented

• • • •

Googling

• • • • •

Profile

Passionate software engineering graduate from the Cape Peninsula University of Technology with 3 years of experience in software development. Creative full-stack engineer who prices on details and achievement. Seeking to use acquired skills in JavaScript, PHP, and C#, and to learn about multiple techs.

Employment History

Programming Tutor, CPUT

Aug 2018 — Aug 2019

© Cape Town, South Africa

I tutored students who had difficulties in mathematics and programming. My job was to help them understanding the basics of C++ which we used to build embedded system with Arduino.

Intern software developer, Nona digital

I worked at Nona digital as an intern software developer.

I started at a QA position where I wrote the end to end test for the site and was later on the front-end side of projects, where I restyled some important part of the website I was working on.

And finally, I tested the entire project using the Cypress library.

I worked as a front-end developer in projects such as

www.gostackr.com, www.go2africa.com

Junior Software developer, Codeswop

I worked at Codeswop as a front-end developer.

During my spell at Codeswop, the MeditPet project I worked on had to go through some refactoring, and using my knowledge of React and Redux, we changed some functionality and styling across the site.

Frontend Software developer, Fireworkx

Sep 2021 − Present © Cape Town, South Africa

- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.
- Built and implemented different type of innovative software.

Languages

French

• • • • •

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet

Lingala

. . . .

Links

GitHub

My Portfolio

Hobbies

Reading science and technology books Coding and learning new languages Playing piano Singing in a choir Doing sport (soccer, gym) I have worked and am working on different projects, providing my frontend engineering skills, applying javascript, HTML and CSS in projects such as:

- Santamre (www-acc.santamre.com)
- Santam.co.za
- MandG (Prudential)
- AndyCab

Frontend Software developer, Smartsplash 360

May 2023 − Present © Cape Town

As a front-end software developer at Smart Splash 360, I leverage Nuxt 3, Typescript, and Tailwind CSS to transform UI/UX designs into interactive interfaces, seamlessly integrating with a PHP back-end.

Education

Mater Dei, Matric

 $Imajored\ in\ Biology\ and\ chemistry, combined\ with\ mathematics, physics\ and\ communication\ skills$

UNIKIN, Preparatory Polytechnic

I started my electrical engineering path in Polytechnic at the University of Kinshasa where I acquired mathematical, and physical skills

I learned how to have a logical thinking and a problem solving mentality, how to approach complex mathematical and physical problems

Cape Peninsula University of Technology, National Diploma

My electrical engineering studies at CPUT helped me to clearly understand the concept of electrical engineering and better embrace the computer system world, including Network, IT essential and Programming.

LinkedIn Learning, Udemy, W3School and Edx

Aug 2019 − Present Online

As an intern at Nona digital, I studied basics and advanced topics about programming languages such as

- JavaScript (ReactJS, VueJS Express NodeJS, GraphQL, Socket.io)
- PHP (OOP-PHP, Laravel)
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- SCSS, Sass
- Asp.net core

Computer Skills

Frontend stack

- HTML, CSS (SCSS, Sass, TailwindCSS)
- Bootstrap, JQuery, MATERIAL UI
- JavaScript (ECMAScript, DOM manipulation)
- React.JS (React Hooks, Context, Redux, Styled Component, React-bootstrap)
- Next JS (Server Side Rendering)
- Vue.JS (Routing, Pinia state management, Vue-router, Composition API)
- NuxtJS (Server Side Rendering)
- Third-party:

Git, GitHub, NPM, yarn, GitLab, Slack, JIRA, Agile, Composer, ...

Backend stack

- Node.Js: (ExpressJs, Socket.io, GraphQL)
- GraphQL: (GraphQL-yoga, Prisma ORM, GraphQL-express)
- PHP: (Laravel, WordPress)
- Java: (Basics of Java Concepts, OOP)
- C# .net : (Basic concepts, OOP, currently learning ASP.net Core)
- Meteor Js: (A JavaScript full-stack framework)

Database (Oracle, MySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft Access)

I have worked with Oracle and MySQL during my university years and beyond those years, I have enhanced the skills I acquired at university from my studies

I learned MongoDB and built couple of projects using it.

Agile Methodology

 $During\ my\ internship\ I\ learned\ and\ applied\ the\ Agile\ methodology\ while\ working\ in\ projects.$

Using Jira board, standups, Slack, and Sprint

References

Richard Miles

Team Lead and Senior Developer at Atheneum Partners

richlloydmiles@gmail.com

Quinton Arendse

Project Manager Fireworkx

+27 73 388 6045